<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://marceaguilar.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://marceaguilar.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-09-01T16:42:06+00:00</updated><id>https://marceaguilar.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Meet Mia: An AI Mentor for Microentrepreneurs</title><link href="https://marceaguilar.github.io/blog/2025/mia-mentor/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Meet Mia: An AI Mentor for Microentrepreneurs"/><published>2025-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://marceaguilar.github.io/blog/2025/mia-mentor</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://marceaguilar.github.io/blog/2025/mia-mentor/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="who-is-mia">Who is Mia?</h2> <p><strong>Mia is a 24/7 AI mentor that lives on WhatsApp.</strong> She helps microentrepreneurs in the informal economy improve how they run their businesses—through friendly, simple, and practical guidance rooted in ILO’s <em><a href="https://www.ilo.org/publications/siyb-implementation-guide">Start and Improve Your Business (SIYB)</a></em> curriculum.</p> <h3 id="real-conversations-mia-talks-with-entrepreneurs">Real Conversations: Mia Talks with Entrepreneurs</h3> <p>Sometimes, text isn’t enough. Mia also supports <strong>voice interactions</strong> — a powerful feature for entrepreneurs who prefer to speak or listen rather than type and read.</p> <p>Below is an example from the field:</p> <div class="row"> <div class="col-md-6"> <h5><i class="fa-solid fa-microphone-lines"></i> Entrepreneur's Voice Note</h5> <audio controls=""> <source src="/assets/audio/mia/empresario1.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/> Your browser does not support the audio element. </audio> <p class="caption mt-2">An entrepreneur asks Mia for help understanding how to price her handmade goods.</p> </div> <div class="col-md-6"> <h5><i class="fa-solid fa-robot"></i> Mia's Audio Reply</h5> <audio controls=""> <source src="/assets/audio/mia/mia_responde1.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/> </audio> <p class="caption mt-2">Mia responds with tailored guidance on pricing strategies based on costs and competition.</p> </div> </div> <h2 id="what-can-mia-do">What Can Mia Do?</h2> <p>Mia engages in interactive conversations with entrepreneurs about:</p> <ul> <li>Marketing</li> <li>Costing and pricing</li> <li>Financial management</li> <li>Business planning</li> <li>Inventory</li> <li>Human resource management</li> </ul> <p>She doesn’t just <em>tell</em> entrepreneurs what to do, she works <em>with them</em> through questions, examples, and calculators.</p> <blockquote> <p><em>“Carla, let’s calculate your break-even point together. Can you tell me your fixed costs for the month?”</em></p> </blockquote> <h2 id="why-it-matters">Why It Matters</h2> <p>Most small businesses in the informal economy lack access to tailored training or mentorship. Mia fills that gap by offering:</p> <ul> <li>Continuous support (day and night)</li> <li>Personalized business logic</li> <li>Financial framing to build <strong>financial acumen at scale</strong></li> </ul> <h2 id="real-voices-from-the-field">Real Voices from the Field</h2> <blockquote> <p><em>“Gracias Mia. Ahora sí entiendo cuánto debo cobrar para no perder.”</em><br/> (<strong>translation</strong>: <em>Thanks, Mia. Now I finally understand how much I should charge without losing money</em>) — Entrepreneur participant from Honduras</p> </blockquote> <hr/> <blockquote> <p><em>“Mia me ha ayudado muchísimo, no solo en el plan de negocios, sino también para tener nuevos clientes y sacar mis costos.”</em><br/> (<strong>translation</strong>: <em>Mia has helped me so much, not only with my business plan, but also with getting new clients and understanding my costs.</em>) — Entrepreneur participant from Honduras</p> </blockquote> <hr/> <blockquote> <p><em>“Estoy feliz con Mia. ¡Se ha vuelto mi mejor amiga en mi negocio!”</em><br/> (<strong>translation</strong>: <em>I’m so happy with Mia. She’s become my best friend in my business!</em>) — Entrepreneur participant from Honduras</p> </blockquote> <hr/> <h2 id="behind-the-scenes">Behind the Scenes</h2> <p>Stay tuned for our upcoming results on how Mia is transforming entrepreneurial learning!</p> <p>If you’re curious about how she works, or want to collaborate, reach out!</p> ]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="AI Mentor"/><category term="Business training"/><category term="Entrepreneurship"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[How Mia helps small businesses thrive with AI-powered guidance]]></summary></entry></feed>